A Guide to the Ledgers and Index Volume for Hurt's Store and D.H. Barbour & Co., Pittsylvania County, Va., 1870-1910
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Ledgers and Index Volume for Hurt's Store and D.H. Barbour & Co., Pittsylvania County, Va. 1870-1910
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
790
This collection consists of 44 volumes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of John L. Hurt, Jr., Hurt, Virginia, April 1940.
Scope and Content
The Hurt's Store - D. H. Barbour and Co. ledgers consist of 44 volumes, dating from 1870-1910. They are chiefly day-books and customer accounts from Hurt's Store in Pittsylvania County, Virginia.
Arrangement
In order to facilitate research, ledgers have been divided into three chronologically arranged series and the volumes have been numbered.
Series I. Hurt's Store - D. H. Barbour Co. Daybooks and chronological ledgers, 1871-1903, vols. 1-23.
Series II. Hurt's Store - D. H. Barbour Co. Customer accounts, ledgers recorded by name, ca. 1881-1910, and n.d., vols. 24-35 Material included a volume of general accounts (vol.33), and a 1907 inventory (vol.34).
Series III. Ledgers kept in Bacon's Castle, Surrey County, Virginia. Daybooks and customer accounts, ca. 1851-1908 and n.d., vols. 36-44.
Contents List
- Series I: Daybooks and Chronological Ledgers
  - 1871 Jan - Dec, 1 (Box 1)
  - 1878 Jan - 1881 Jun, 2 (Box 1)
  - 1881 Mar - 1883 Jun, 3 (Box 1)
  - 1882 Jan - Sep, 4 (Box 1)
  - 1883 Jun - Nov, 5 (Box 1)
  - 1884 Apr - 1885 Apr, 6 (Box 1)
  - 1885 Oct - Aug, 7 (Box 2)
  - 1886 Aug - Dec, 8 (Box 2)
  - 1887 Jan - Sep, 9 (Box 2)
  - 1888 Jun - Dec, 10 (Box 2)
  - 1889 Apr - Jun, 11 (Box 2)
  - 1889 Jun - Sep, 12 (Box 3)
  - 1890 Apr - Jun, 13 (Box 3)
  - 1890 Jun - Nov, 14 (Box 3)
  - 1890 Nov - 1891 Apr, 15 (Box 3)
  - 1891 Jan - Dec, 16 (Box 3)
  - 1894 Nov - 1895 Dec, 17 (Box 4)
  - 1895 Sep - 1896 Jun, 18 (Box 4)
  - 1896 Sep - 1897 Oct, 19 (Box 4)
  - 1898 Sep - Dec, 20 (Box 4)
  - 1899 Jan - Oct, 21 (Box 4)
  - 1901 Mar - 1908 Aug, 22 (Box 4)
  - 1902 fall - 1903 spring, 23 (Box 4)
- Series II: Customer Accounts and Ledgers Recorded by Name
  - ca. 1881 - 1882, 24 (Box 4)
  - ca. 1881 - 1885, 25 (Box 4)
  - ca. 1882 - 1888, 26 (Box 4)
  - ca. 1884 - 1886, 27 (Box 5)
  - ca. 1885 - 1887, 28 (Box 5)
  - ca. 1886 - 1887, 29 (Box 5)
  - ca. 1886 - 1889, 30 (Box 5)
  - ca. 1889 - 1890, 31 (Box 6)
  - ca. 1891 - 1892, 32 (Box 6)
  - ca. 1901-1910, 33 (Box 6)
  - ca. 1907, 34 (Box 6)
  - n.d., 35 (Box 6)
- Series III: Daybooks and Customer Accounts
  - ca. 1851 - 1855, 36 (Box 7)
  - 1852 Apr - 1853 May, 37 (Box 7)
  - 1852 May - 1853 May, 38 (Box 7)
  - ca. 1853, 39 (Box 7)
  - ca. 1853 - 1858, 40 (Box 8)
  - 1878 Apr - 1884 May, 41 (Box 8)
  - 1901 Jan - 1908 Jul, 42 (Box 8)
  - n.d., 43 (Box 8)
  - n.d., 44 (Box 8)